# Resume/CV

#### **Devin Austin**

devin.austin@gmail.com 970-290-6669

# Summary: I am a web software developer.

I build web applications. I learn quickly. I'm extremely tenacious when it comes to getting things done and figuring things out. I have experience with high pressure situations that require fast action, precise movements and critical thinking skills. Good software is developed by combining research, planning, quick iterations, testing, and communication. I build the best product that is possible, in the time given. I make sure I have the tools and knowledge required to do so.

Give me a specification, I will do everything in my power to produce a reusable, extensible, fast, and efficient solution; on time, and with a smile.

#### **Skills**

## Languages

- Java
- Python
- C#
- Ruby
- Go

## Applications/Technologies

- AWS
  - S3, RDS/Aurora, IAM policies, SSM documents, EC2, KMS secrets, Cloudformation
- Various SQL database flavors (Postgres, MySQL)
- Ansible
- Terraform

# **Professional Experience**

## **April 2018 - Present Enlitic**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

- Architected, planned and built out tooling to help data scientists manage deep learning modeling code snapshots
- Consulted and improved build and deploy processes for various applications
- Advised on AWS practices

#### October 2016 - April 2018 Ancestry.com

## DNA Data Science Platform - Senior Software Engineer

• Extracted EC2 orchestration functionality from a Spring Boot application into its own application and extended its functionality

- Set up a build system using Jenkins 2 Pipelines to deploy the application to EC2 instances running Docker on CoreOS
- Used Terraform to set up all required IAM roles, policies, and other resources (S3 buckets, Aurora clusters, SSM documents)
- Handled every aspect of the aforementioned application from designing and implementing both application and infrastructure architecture
- Successfully launched beta version of orchestration application to a select group of scientists after overcoming a lot of infrastructure adversity with minimal support

# **DNA Platform - Senior Software Engineer**

- Designed and implemented a Spring Boot Java application to manage provisioning EC2 instances for DNA scientists, saving the team about 3 months of training and development time.
- Set up a more robust build system for an existing application that helped through numerous deployments and disasters.
- Mentored junior and less experienced developers through various application development systems, deployment procedures and coding best practices.
- Built out and configured several build and deploy environments using Jenkins pipelines, EC2, git, Docker and bash.
- Wrote a blue/green deployment script in bash to handle deployments in AWS

## August 2012 - October 2016 Ancestry.com

## **Devops - Software Developer**

- Worked on maintaining configuration for DNA application stacks through Chef
- Built various data migration scripts, data transformation scripts, and a small Go cron job that handled kicking off recurring billing jobs.
- Built a tool in go to handle a massive SQL Server data transformation and migration
- Wrote several tools to handle several large image imports and mysql data migrations for an image service that handled several terabytes of image data
- Maintained and added several features to an existing, large, legacy, high traffic image service written in Perl, running on AWS, using MySQL as the metadata backend and S3 for image storage.
- Worked on building a testing framework for a large .NET application using C#, Selenium, Fitnesse and Jenkins.
- Managed configuration, build, and deployment for several applications spanning across Linux, Windows and various different application frameworks. Since there was only a manual process to handle these deployments, I wrote several tools to help make things more stable.
- Deployed Nagios to several disparate systems using Ansible.

## April 2006 - August 2012 CodedRight

## **Independent Contractor/Founder**

- Built several small web applications for various clients' websites using Perl
- Built a document storage web application that was intended to serve as a document sharing website for various businesses in Perl, running on AWS
- Managed and wrote a database and file data migration script in Perl to move data from a previously used
  - OpenInteract application to a new Catalyst+DBIx::Class web application backed by MySQL and MogileFS.
- Built a search engine feature that uses Data::SearchEngine and DBIx::Class to search based on racing class
  - types, race tracks, and other such race track and car class based data. (Perl)

- 7/6/2018
  - Wrote a geocoding feature that calculates the distance of a track from a given city name or zip code and
    - returns tracks within a chosen radius (5, 10, 15 miles etc) of city/zip code based on Geo::Coder and DBIx::Class (Perl)
  - Implemented a materialized path structure for managing virtual directories for website assets and file data in
    - the database based upon DBIx::Class::Tree::Ordered::MaterializedPath, allowing administrators to have a file
    - system view of website assets. (Perl)
  - Developed Catalyst and Ruby on Rails codebase that used a JSON API to pass messages between applications

## January 2012 - April 2012 Ionzero, LLC

## **Software Engineer**

- Worked on a large, legacy Perl application that deals with airline flights locally and internationally.
- Built out features dealing with parsing data coming from airline flight systems such as Sabre.
- Worked on designing and building a metadata storage application for an ad audit service
- Built an application to act as a proxy between a front facing php web application and a storage file system that
  - handles upwards of 6,000 file uploads a day via the API that handles XML, JSON and plain HTTP data. Built
  - using Catalyst and Plack
- Built and designed a proof of concept application for <a href="ChannelMeter.com">ChannelMeter.com</a>, a YouTube analytics website

#### **Education**

#### 2007-2010 Metropolitan State College of Denver Denver, CO

- BS in Computer Security with a minor in Computer Science
- Majored in Computer Security with a Computer Science minor Bachelor of Science in Computer Security and Crime
- Participated in CANVAS A network security exploitation convention/workshop two years in a row. Contributed to breaking into servers via multiple exploits, SQL injection, DCOM holes, etc. Placed 4th, and 3rd respectively.

#### 2006-2007 University of Northern Colorado Greeley, CO

## **Open Source Work**

• http://github.com/dhoss

# **Software I've written:**

- <u>ceramiccatepottery.com</u> An image gallery and administrative interface for my wife's pottery business. Built using Java (Spark Web framework + jooq), Postgresql 9.4, Varnish, Cloudflare CDN, Nginx and Ansible. Using webpack to manage static assets.
- <u>Treeify</u> A gem to allow you to make recursive queries using Postgres and CTE (WITH RECURSIVE, to be more precise) and get a tree-like data structure in return.
- Fluorescent A small gem to highlight search terms in search results.

#### **Identities and resources**

#### Writing

Resume - Devin Austin

Published many articles regarding perl, a few of which are listed here:

<u>Playing With Scala, part 1</u> and <u>part 2</u> - A tutorial on how to get the Scala version of the Play! framework set up under Postgres specs2 for testing, using travis-ci for continuous integration testing. It was generally well received on the scala subreddit on <u>reddit.com</u>, and I actually received some email correspondence and comments on the article from the Slick author himself with some advice and praise on the article.

Simple Photo Gallery in Catalyst

Next Page Redirect after Login

Plack and Catalyst

Trees in SQL with Catalyst

The New Catalyst ScriptRunner API